JACOB BULLOCH - DEVOPS ENGINEER

(575) 607-5483

JPBulloch@pm.me

Web-Based Resume

Coding Experience

- Azure DevOps 9mo
- Java 3mo
- Python 3mo

- Git 6mo
- Ansible 3mo
- Docker 6mo

- PostgreSQL 3mo
- SonarCloud 3mo
- Azure 3mo

Projects

Automating Agile

06/2021

Azure DevOps Repo

Role: DevOps Engineer

Description:

An existing Java application is augmented with tooling to support Agile values in a DevOps workflow with CI/CD. The servlet-based application exposes simple CRUD operations using a custom ORM library that's versioned and published from a separate code repository. A project board, containerization, static analysis, and documentation contribute to short feedback loops and higher product quality.

Tools/Technologies:

Azure DevOps, Docker, PostgreSQL, Ansible, Java, Tomcat, Git, SonarCloud, Bash, SSH

Pushing Python

Git Hub Repo

06/2021

Roles: Python Developer, DevOps Engineer

Description:

A proof-of-concept implementation of a relational database is built using pure-Python by leveraging native Python data-structures, chiefly dicts, to mimic the behavior of an SQL database. The application is deployed via Ansible playbooks to multiple virtual-machines, installing needed dependencies on the remote hosts and ensuring the correct version of Python (version 3.9) is properly configured. Version control and code deployment are provided by Git.

Tools/Technologies:

Python3, Python-venv, Pip, Ansible, Bash, SSH, Git

About Me

A mentor advised me to consider what I most enjoyed doing when I was 13 years old and find a job that does that. For me, that is coding! My experience with foreign language acquisition has helped me transition between programming languages and paradigms (e.g., BASIC, Haskell, C++, Java, Python).

DevOps Engineering leverages my ability to navigate between languages and my experience with process engineering. I focus on improving the process around the objective and the objective itself. I derive job satisfaction from removing roadblocks to deliver quality continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD).

Interesting facts:

- I am Quadrilingual (English, Spanish, Korean, and Arabic)
- > I run a mile most mornings to start my day
- I met my wife in a show-choir in college; we've been married for 13 years

Personal Git Repository: https://github.com/jpbulloch5

Work History

Military Outreach Coordinator

07/2018 – Present Eastern New Mexico University

Portales, NM

- Mitigated critical issue from cohort benefit rule changes; prevented 80% loss by preemptive correction
- Developed/implemented cohort statistical tracking; automated usable data analysis/output from raw data
- Designed cohort student experience priorities; boosted enrollment 522% in 2 years with grassroots effort

Direct Support Operator; Team Leader

04/2015 - 07/2018

Air Force Special Operations Command

Cannon AFB, NM

- Led team of 13; directed professional development, productivity, mission readiness, and compliance
- · Liaised between organizations; showcased capabilities/services via planning, exercises, and real missions
- Developed training materials to cover deficit; boosted initial pass rate 25%; saved 160 person-hours

Section Leader: Foreign Language Acquisition Course

08/2013 - 04/2015

Air Education and Training Command

Presidio of Monterey, CA

- Led six students in intense 18-month Arabic Language Acquisition Program; guided study habits/priorities
- Developed supplementary Arabic Language training materials for students awaiting official class start
- Coached section to 83% pass rate; 33% higher than expected 50% attrition rate; most successful section

Foreign Area Specialist: Analysis Operator

07/2011 - 08/2013

Air Combat Command

Davis-Monthan AFB, AZ

- Briefed aircrews as Foreign Area subject matter expert; optimized mission effectiveness/crew knowledge
- Translated, analyzed, and reported time-sensitive foreign language material; swift judgment calls required
- Maintained sensitive military information in accordance with strict protocols; Top-Secret SCI clearance

Education History

BS – Computer Science Minor: Graphic Design

05/2021 Eastern New Mexico University Portales, NM

Graduated Magna Cum Laude

AA – Arabic

12/2014 Defense Language Institute Monterey, CA

Graduated with Honors

AAS – Intelligence Studies and Technology

07/2013 Community College of the Air Force Montgomery, AL

AA – Korean

10/2010 Defense Language Institute Monterey, CA

Additional Education Information ENMU Official Graduation Transcript